<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A declaration of the right honourable the Lord Major, aldermen, and Common-Councell of the City of London, concerning the great and apparent danger of the said city, and the desires and proceedings of the Common-Councell-men therin, in behalf of the citizens. Also, their present summons and directions (in His Majesties name) to the trained bands and citizens, touching the preservation of the peace, defence of themselves, the city, and the magistrates thereof. Agreed upon by the honourable court at Guild-Hall, on Tuesday last, April 25. 1648. Michel.</title>
            <author>City of London (England). Court of Common Council.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1648</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 10 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A82232</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing D764</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E437_2</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R204682</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99864147</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99864147</idno>
            <idno type="VID">161625</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A82232)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 161625)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 69:E437[2])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A declaration of the right honourable the Lord Major, aldermen, and Common-Councell of the City of London, concerning the great and apparent danger of the said city, and the desires and proceedings of the Common-Councell-men therin, in behalf of the citizens. Also, their present summons and directions (in His Majesties name) to the trained bands and citizens, touching the preservation of the peace, defence of themselves, the city, and the magistrates thereof. Agreed upon by the honourable court at Guild-Hall, on Tuesday last, April 25. 1648. Michel.</title>
                  <author>City of London (England). Court of Common Council.</author>
                  <author>R. V.</author>
                  <author>T. H.</author>
                  <author>England and Wales. Parliament.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 6 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for R.W.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>MDCXLVIII.[1648]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Contains three letters: The first the Lord Mayor's announcement, in black letter, dated: 25. April, 1648; the second dated and signed: Barwick 19 April, 1648. R.V.; the third dated and signed: Carmarthen 19. April 1648. TH.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Civil War, 1642-1649 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>London (England) --  Defenses --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-01</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-02</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-02</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:161625:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A DECLARATION OF The Right Honourable the Lord Major, Aldermen, and Common-Councell of the City of LONDON, CONCERNING The great and apparent danger of the ſaid City, and the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſires and proceedings of the Common-Councell-men therein, in behalf of the Citizens.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>ALSO,</hi> Their preſent Summons and Directions (in His Majeſties Name) to the Trained Bands and Citizens, touching the preſervation of the Peace, defence of them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, the City, and the Magiſtrates thereof.</p>
            <p>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="license">
                        <p>AGreed upon by the Honourable Court at <hi>Guild-Hall,</hi> on <hi>Tueſday</hi> laſt, <hi>April</hi> 25. 1648.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>MICHEL.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </p>
            <figure>
               <figDesc>blazon of the City of London</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON:</hi> Printed for <hi>R. W.</hi> MDCXLVIII.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="document">
            <pb facs="tcp:161625:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:161625:2"/>
            <head>A DECLARATION OF The Right Honourable the Lord Mayor, Aldermen, and Common-Councel of the City of LONDON: IN The Name of the Kings moſt Excellent Majeſty; c<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>n<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceming their preſent Reſolution to preſerve and defend the ſaid City and Inhabitants.</head>
            <p>VPon the 24. and 25. of this in ſtant <hi>Aprill,</hi> 1648. the Right Honourable the Lord Mayor, Aldermen, and Common-councell of the City of <hi>London,</hi> had a ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nerall meeting at Guild-Hall where they ſpent much time, upon debates and conſultations touching the preſervation of
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:161625:3"/>
the peace, defence of themſelves, the City, and the Magi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrates thereof; as alſo concerning the apparent danger, that the city is now in at the preſent. Therefore, according to the deſire, and direction of the ſaid Court, the Right Hono<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable the Lord Mayor agreed upon this enſuing Declarati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, and ordered that it ſhould be printed and publiſhed, to the end, that all upon ſight thereof, doe ſo order and diſpoſe of their ſervants, and all others under their charge, that they be not onely kept from committing any outrage or miſde<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>meanour; but that they and their ſervants be in a readineſſe according to their ſeveral capacities, with Arms, Weapons, and Ammunition, for preſervation and defence of the ſaid City; a Copy of the ſaid Declaration I ſhall here give you verbatim.</p>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="declaration_of_the_City_of_London">
                        <head>BY THE MAJOR.</head>
                        <p>FOraſmuch, as it is conceived and apprehended by the Common-councell, that the City at the preſent is in great danger; Theſe are therefore, according to the Deſire and Direction of the ſaid Court to will and require you in his Majeſties Name, That preſently vpon ſight hereof, you reſpectively, with the Conſtables of your ſeveral Precincts, do repair to every Houſholder within the ſame, and give them ſtrict charge and command, that at their perils, they doe ſo order and diſpoſe of their Servants, and all others vnder their charge, that they be not only kept from committing any
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:161625:3"/>
outrage or miſdemeanour; But that they and their ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vants from time to time be in readineſſe, according to their ſeverall capacities<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> with Armes, Weapons, and Ammunitions for preſervation of the Peace, defence of themſelves, the City, and the Magiſtrates thereof: And alſo, that all Perſons who are of the Trained Bands of this City, Do from time to time upon the beat of the Drum, repair with all ſpeed to their Colours: And therein demeaſn themſelves as may conduce to the ſafe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and welfare of this City.</p>
                        <p>And that you do from time to time certifie vnto me, or ſome other of his Majeſties Juſtices of the Peace, the Names of ſuch <hi>Conſtables,</hi> and others, as you ſhall finde to be remiſſe or negligent in the performance of their re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpective Duties in this behalfe, to the intent, that they may be puniſhed according to the ſame. And hereof fails you not, as you tender the ſafety of your ſelves and the <hi>City,</hi> and will anſwer the contrary at your perill.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <dateline>
                              <date>This 25. of <hi>April,</hi> 1648.</date>
                           </dateline>
                           <signed>MICHEL.</signed>
                        </closer>
                        <trailer>To the Deputy, Common-Councell-men, and Conſtables in the Ward of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 span">
                              <desc>〈1 span left blank〉</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </trailer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>
               <pb facs="tcp:161625:4"/>
BY Letters from Scotland it is further certified, That at <hi>Edinburgh</hi> the expectation of the malignants are great, and reports variable, but little concluded on: only we hear that they are reſolved, that an army ſhal be ſent into Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land, and although many wil not be perſwaded to believe it, yet it may now more eaſily be gathered, that ſuch a thing is intended, and wil ſpeedily be effected, if not prevented; for the Scots army draws Southward, and many of them are ordered to be quartered neer the Borders, the Lord <hi>Belca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rouſe</hi> Troop have taken up their quarters within five miles of Berwick, having order ſo to doe. Many other Troopes have quarters aſſigned them in the South of Scotland, and eſpecialy in the Townes and Villages nrer adjoyning to <hi>England;</hi> alſo from other parts of Scotland we perceive the Scots Forces to creep Southward, but they are wary, and do it by little and little, the better to avoid ſuſpition, but if their intents are, as is ſuſpected, <hi>England</hi> may chance to fruſtrate their deſigns, and the Scots after all their jugling be decei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved of their expectations.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>The Parliament of</hi> Scotland <hi>have given anſwer to the</hi> Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſh Commiſſioners <hi>papers, but it is ſaid to be very unſatis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>factory<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and that they refer the ſubſtance of all to their own</hi> Commiſſioners <hi>who are comming into</hi> England, <hi>of whom the Lord</hi> Lec <hi>is one to treat with the Parliament, and have</hi> Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſitions <hi>and inſtructions given them,</hi> to treat about ſetling Religion according to the Covenant for the King his remo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vall to one of his houſes, and a perſonall treaty with him; as alſo for disbanding the Army, and other Propoſitions that I have not as yet; the certainty of the difference between the Clergy and ſtate is as great as ever, they will by no meanes conſent to the raiſing of men, although liſting in divers parts of this Kingdome; 'tis ſuppoſed 'twill be ſpee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dily effected; and becauſe many of the Commanders of the ſtanding Forces of this Kingdome do not concur with them in this deſign, thoſe Forces are to be disbanded, and the Earl
<pb facs="tcp:161625:4"/>
of <hi>Calender</hi> is to be General of their new <hi>Modell;</hi> inſomuch, that the Cavees and Engliſh Fugitives grow very high, trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting ruine and deſtruction to the Parliament and their Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>herents.</p>
            <p>But indeed, ſome dayes there are great hopes of an agreement, and other days the diſtance is ſo farre, as ſcarce any man ſhal know how neer they are to have an Army: ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Engliſh men are at Edenburgh, and they doe dayly in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creaſe. Another great ſhip came to Leeth Rode on Fryday night laſt; what ſhe is, is not yet known, but a flying Report of the Prince being in her, but no certainty. Some Iriſh Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bels are come into ſome of the Scots Iſlands, and the Marq. of <hi>Argyles</hi> Regiment are directed, with ſome others, to march towards them. This is all, I earneſtly requeſt a correſpon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dency weekly, and where I ſhal direct my Letter unto you, that I may take the occaſion to ſubſcribe my ſelf.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Your oblieged ſervant, <hi>R. V.</hi>
               </signed>
               <dateline>Barwick <date>19 April, 1648.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
            <postscript>
               <opener>
                  <salute>SIR,</salute>
               </opener>
               <p>Since the writing hereof we hear that the Parliament of Scotland have given an anſwer to our Commiſſioners pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pers, but it is ſaid to be very unſatisfactory, and that they re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fer the ſubſtance of all to their own Commiſſioners which are comming into <hi>England</hi> to treat with the Parliament.</p>
               <p>IN the Marq. of Argyles Countrey, there is riſen up in Arms one commonly called <hi>Kolkittoh,</hi> which hath cau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed ſome of the Forces that lay in the South of Scotland to march Northward for the ſuppreſſion of them, all the Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers in the ſtanding Army of Scotland except Lieutenant General Middleton) have petitioned to the Parliament, and preſented theſe Propoſals, <hi>viz.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>1. That they will be pleaſed to conſult with the Miniſters of the Kirk, in relation to their
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:161625:5"/>
proceedings touching the Kingdome of <hi>England.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>2. That they will be pleaſed not to ingage in a War againſt <hi>England,</hi> unleſſe the Kirk of <hi>Scotland</hi> doe concur therein.</item>
                  </list>
               </p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>yours, &amp;c.</signed>
               </closer>
            </postscript>
         </div>
         <div type="letter">
            <opener>
               <salute>Sir,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>Since my laſt, we have received further intelligence from South-wales, that Col. <hi>Horton,</hi> and Col. <hi>Lewis</hi> with their Forces have ſtreightned the enemies quarters, &amp; for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ced them to a narrower diſtance, but not without ſome blowes; for, as it is ſaid, they have had a very hot skirmiſh, and reſolutely maintained by both parties, upon ſeverall charges and conflicts; and afrer ſome diſpute Poyers party retreated, our men purſues; ſome are wounded, but no great hurt done. Col. <hi>Flemming</hi> hath lately fell upon the enemy, &amp; took divers priſoners. Col. <hi>Okeys</hi> Dragoons are joyned with Col. <hi>Horton,</hi> they have had a hot skirmiſh with the enemy. By the next you ſhal hear further, from</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Your moſt affectionate friend, <hi>T H.</hi>
               </signed>
               <dateline>Carmarthen <date>19. April 1648.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
            <postscript>
               <p>Imprimatur</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>G. M.</signed>
               </closer>
            </postscript>
         </div>
         <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
